Nicholas D'Angelo Papers
Nicholas D'Angelo Papers
- Scores
  - By D'Angelo
    - Celestial Three for Symphonic Band and Speaker (optional), oversize score (Oversize 16)
    - Child's Prayer for Violoncello Quartet (Oversize 3)
    - Chorale and Alleluia Four-Part Chorus of Mixed Voices (a cappella) (Box 2)
    - Concerto for Orchestra (in one movement) (Box 2)
    - Concerto for Orchestra (in one movement), oversize score (Oversize 3)
    - Concerto for Orchestra (in one movement), oversize parts (Oversize 4)
    - Concerto for Orchestra (in one movement), oversize score (Oversize 16)
    - Connotations Six for Piano (Box 2)
    - Divertimento for Flute, B-flat Clarinet, Strings and Timpani, oversize score, parts, proof (reverse print) (Oversize 3)
    - Dreams and Darkness for Wind Ensemble (Oversize 16)
    - Echoes and Visions for Chamber Orchestra, Parts (Box 2)
    - Echoes and Visions for Chamber Orchestra, oversize score (Oversize 3)
    - Echoes and Visions for Chamber Orchestra, oversize score (Oversize 16)
    - Echoes of Ancients for Solo Violin (Oversize 3)
    - Echoes Six for Chorus and Wind Ensemble (Box 2)
    - Echoes Six for Chorus and Wind Ensemble, oversize score, proof (oversize) (Oversize 3)
    - Expectations for Mixed Chorus & Chamber Orchestra (Box 2)
    - Expectations for Mixed Chorus & Chamber Orchestra, oversize score (Oversize 5)
    - Fable and Dance for E-flat Alto Saxophone and Piano (Box 2)
    - Fable and Dance for E-flat Alto Saxophone and Piano, oversize score (Oversize 5)
    - Fantasy on Two Christmas Tunes, oversize score, proof (Oversize) (Oversize 5)
    - Four Conversations for String Quartet (Oversize 5)
    - Four Times Two Haiku of Basho for Soprano, Brass Ensemble and Percussion (Oversize 5)
    - Hymn for Spacemen for Chorus and Brass Ensemble (Box 2)
    - Hymn for Spacemen for Mixed Chorus and Organ (Box 2)
    - Idyll for Violin, 'Cello and Piano (Oversize 5)
    - Impressions Two for Band (Box 2)
    - Impressions Two for Band, oversize score, parts (Oversize 6)
    - Introduction and Fantasy for E-flat Alto Saxophone and Piano (Box 2)
    - Introduction and Fantasy for E-flat Alto Saxophone and Piano, oversize score, part (for saxophone) (Oversize 6)
    - Introduction and Seriate Variants for Wind Ensemble (Box 3)
    - Introduction and Seriate Variants for Wind Ensemble, oversize score (Oversize 7)
    - Jump for the Sun for Saxophone Quartet (Oversize 7)
    - Kandinsky Variation for Piano (Box 3)
    - Kandinsky Variation for Piano, oversize score (Oversize 7)
    - Light that Fills the Void for Wind Quintet (Box 3)
    - Light that Fills the Void for Wind Quintet, Score, parts (Oversize 7)
    - Love's Labour's Won, Three Sonnets of Shakespeare for Soprano and Piano (Box 3)
    - Love's Labour's Won, Three Sonnets of Shakespeare for Soprano and Piano, oversize score (Oversize 8)
    - Mais Ces Oiseaux for High Voice, Flute, B-flat Clarinet, Bassoon and Piano, oversize score, proof (Oversize 8)
    - Masks of Innocence for B-flat Clarinet and Piano (Oversize 8)
    - Metaluna, and Beyond (Box 3)
    - Miniature for Flute and Piano (Oversize 8)
    - Mosaics for Flute, B-flat Bass Clarinet, Violin, 'Cello and Piano (Oversize 8)
    - Mosaics for Violin, 'Cello, B-flat Clarinet, Bassoon and Piano (Oversize 8)
    - National Guardian (Concert Marche) (Oversize 8)
    - No Sad Songs for Julie for Wind Ensemble (Box 3)
    - No Sad Songs for Julie for Wind Ensemble, oversize score, parts (incomplete) (Oversize 8)
    - Of Voices and Winds for Concert Band and Chorus (S.A.T.B.) Three Songs of Love, Score + S.A.T.B./Piano Part (Box 3)
    - Of Voices and Winds for Concert Band and Chorus (S.A.T.B.) Three Songs of Love, oversize score, parts (partial) (Oversize 9)
    - Other Enchantments for Solo Violin (Oversize 9)
    - Other Enchantments for Unaccompanied Violin (Box 3)
    - Painted Words for Soprano and Piano (Box 3)
    - Pastorale for Baritone Horn (Trombone Opt.) and Piano (Box 4)
    - Prelude in A Minor for Orchestra (Box 4)
    - Prelude in A Minor for Orchestra, oversize score (Oversize 9)
    - Prelude, Chorale and March for Band (a Bicentennial Triptych) (Box 4)
    - Psalms Triptych for Soprano, Chorus, Brass Ensemble, Percussion and Organ (optional) (Box 4)
    - Psalms Triptych for Soprano, Chorus, Brass Ensemble, Percussion and Organ (optional), oversize score (Oversize 9)
    - Purple Lace, Draft score (Oversize 9)
    - Quintet for Winds [No. 2] (Box 4)
    - Quintet for Winds [No. 2], oversize score (Oversize 9)
    - Quintet for Winds No. 4 (Box 4)
    - Quintet for Winds No. 4, Parts (Oversize 9)
    - Seven Secrets Sublime for Chamber Orchestra (Box 4)
    - Seventh Star of Paracelsus' for B-flat Clarinet, Violin, Cello and Piano (Box 4)
    - Seventh Star of Paracelsus' for B-flat Clarinet, Violin, Cello and Piano, proof (Oversize 10)
    - Sing a Song of Six for Mixed Chorus and Piano (Box 5)
    - Six Figures for B-flat Clarinet and Piano (Box 5)
    - Six Figures for B-flat Clarinet and Piano, oversize score (Oversize 10)
    - Six Mobiles for Pirandello for Brass Quintet and Piano (Box 5)
    - Some Summer Sun for Solo Flute (Box 5)
    - Some Summer Sun for Solo Flute, oversize score (Oversize 10)
    - Sonata for B-flat Clarinet and Piano (Box 5)
    - Sonata for B-flat Clarinet and Piano, Part for clarinet (Oversize 10)
    - Sonata for Violin and Piano (Beyond the Mirror) (Box 5)
    - Sonata for Violin and Piano (Beyond the Mirror), oversize score (Oversize 10)
    - Sonatina for Violin and Orchestra, oversize score, proof (Oversize 10)
    - Sonatina for Violin and Piano (Box 5)
    - Sonatina for Violin and Piano, oversize score, proof (Oversize 10)
    - Songs my Mother Never Sang to Me…and Other Stuff (Box 5)
    - Songs…I Never Sang for My Father for Cantori (Box 5)
    - Sonoria No. 1 for Tenor Solo, Chorus S.A.T.B., B-flat Clarinet and Piano (Box 6)
    - Sonoria No. 1 for Tenor Solo, Chorus S.A.T.B., B-flat Clarinet and Piano, oversize score (Oversize 11)
    - Sonoria No. 2 a Musical Drama in Three Acts for Soprano and Baritone Soloists, S.A.T.B., Chorus, Brass, Percussion, Harp and Piano (Box 6)
    - Sonoria No. 2 a Musical Drama in Three Acts for Soprano and Baritone Soloists, S.A.T.B., Chorus, Brass, Percussion, Harp and Piano, oversize score (Oversize 16)
    - Stanzas from Walt Whitmans Song of the Universal for Chorus (S.A.T.B.), Band, and Orchestra (Oversize 11)
    - String Quartet No. 2, Proof (reverse-print) of score and parts (Oversize 11)
    - String Quartet No. 3 (Box 6)
    - String Quartet No. 3 (in one movement), oversize score, parts (Oversize 11)
    - String Quartet No. 4 (Box 6)
    - String Quartet No. 4, oversize score (Oversize 11)
    - String Quartet No. 5 Thus Speaks the Discoverer (Oversize 16)
    - String Quartet No. 6 in Two Movements (Box 6)
    - String Quartet No. 7 (Inferocire) in Two Movements (Box 6)
    - String Quartet No. 7 (Inferocire) in Two Movements, oversize score (Oversize 11)
    - String Quartet No. 8 (Music of Night with Moon) (Box 6)
    - String Quartet No. 8 (Music of Night with Moon), oversize score, parts (Oversize 12)
    - String Quintet (Voices of Silence) (Oversize 12)
    - Symphony No. 2 for Orchestra and Chorus (the Civil War) (Box 7)
    - Symphony No. 2 for Orchestra and Chorus (the Civil War), Proof (oversize) (Oversize 12)
    - Symphony No. 3 An Ode of Dedication for Solo Voices, Chorus, Organ, Harpsichord and Orchestra (Box 7)
    - Symphony No. 3 An Ode of Dedication for Solo Voices, Chorus, Organ, Harpsichord and Orchestra, oversize score, proof (Oversize 12)
    - Symphony No. 4, proof (parts only) (Oversize 13)
    - Symphony No. 4 for Orchestra (Box 7)
    - Symphony No. 6 (Temple of the Sky) for Symphonic Wind Ensemble (Oversize 13)
    - Symphony No. 6 (Temple of the Sky) for Wind Ensemble (Oversize 13)
    - Temples and Tombs, Proof (Oversize) (Oversize 13)
    - Temples of the Sky for Symphonic Wind Ensemble (Box 7)
    - Ten Birds of Brass for B-flat Trumpet, French Horn and Trombone (Box 7)
    - Ten Birds of Brass for B-flat Trumpet, French Horn and Trombone, oversize score (Oversize 13)
    - Things of Remembrance Past, Score + Parts (Box 7)
    - Things of Remembrance Past, oversize score (Oversize 13)
    - Things of Remembrance Past, oversize score (Oversize 16)
    - Three Fantasies on Three Themes of Picasso (Box 7)
    - Three Fantasies on Three Themes of Picasso, oversize score (Oversize 13)
    - Thus Speaks the Discoverer or Chamber Orchestra (Oversize 16)
    - Time After Time for Jazz Choir & Jazz Ensemble (Box 8)
    - Time for Change for Flute and B-flat Clarinet (Box 8)
    - Time for Change for Flute and B-flat Clarinet, oversize score (Oversize 14)
    - Time Passages for Piano (Box 8)
    - Time Passages for Piano, oversize score (Oversize 14)
    - Trio for B-flat Clarinet, Viola, and Piano (Box 8)
    - Trio for B-flat Clarinet, Viola, and Piano, oversize score, parts (Oversize 14)
    - Trio for Violin, Cello, and Piano "Eight Notables", oversize score (Oversize 15)
    - Trio for Violin, Cello, and Piano "Eight Notables", oversize score (Oversize 16)
    - Two Three-Fours for Band I. Spiritual II. Slow Waltz (Box 8)
    - Unicorns, Androsphinxes, Androgynes and Other Mystical Beasts, oversize score (Oversize 15)
    - Variants for E-flat Alto Saxophone and Piano (Box 8)
    - Variations on a Dorian Theme for Flute and Piano, oversize score (Oversize 15)
    - Various Actions for Wind Quintet (Box 8)
    - Visions of the Spirit for B-flat Clarinet, 'Cello and Piano (Box 8)
    - Visions of the Spirit for B-flat Clarinet, 'Cello and Piano, oversize score (Oversize 15)
    - Voices of Janus for Brass Quintet, oversize score (Oversize 15)
    - Whispers of the Moon (Box 8)
    - Whispers of the Moon, oversize score, parts (Oversize 15)
    - Whispers of the Moon, oversize score (Oversize 16)
    - [Incomplete fragments of works] (Oversize 17)
  - By others, title
    - Sally [Mei Chun] Chen: Piece for String Quartet (Oversize 18)
    - Richard Delaney: Four Songs, a Poem by Cesar Vallejo for Soprano and Two Cellos (Oversize 18)
    - Debussy: Golliwogg's Cake-Walk (parts) (arr. Grofe) (Oversize 18)
    - Paul Hindemith: Madrigales (Oversize 18)
    - Burton Lane: Old Devil Moon (arr. by N. D'Angelo) (Oversize 18)
    - Matt Malneck and Robert Maxwell: Shangri-La, a Modern Composition for Piano (parts arr. by N. D'Angelo) (Oversize 18)
    - Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart: Complete String Quartets with the Horn and Clarinet Quintets (Dover Study and Playing Editions), Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging; please refer to to locate this item.
  - By others, instrument
    - Drum (Oversize 19)
    - French Horn (Oversize 19)
    - Saxophone (Alto) (Oversize 19)
    - Saxophone (Alto 2) (Oversize 20)
    - Saxophone (Baritone) (Oversize 20)
    - Saxophone (Tenor) (Oversize 21)
    - Saxophone (Tenor 2) (Oversize 21)
    - Trombone 1 (Oversize 22)
    - Trombone 2 (Oversize 22)
    - Trombone 3 (Oversize 23)
    - Trombone 4 (Oversize 23)
    - Trombone 5/Tuba (Oversize 23)
    - Trumpet 1 (Oversize 24)
    - Trumpet 2 (Oversize 24)
    - Trumpet 3 (Oversize 25)
    - Trumpet 4, 5 (Oversize 25)
- Writings
  - By D'Angelo
    - The Arts in Western Society, 2 copies (Box 9)
    - The Cask of Amontillado (opera lyrics) (Box 9)
      See also Scores: By D'Angelo: Cask of Amontillado
    - A Direct and Practical Approach to Harmonic Grammar, 2 copies (Box 9)
    - Dissertation (D. Ed.), 1977; part 1 is textual, part 2 is a concerto for orchestra; other copies of the concerto also exist in the collection; 2 copies (Box 9)
    - Erwartung: An Example of Arnold Schoenberg's Response to the Expressionistic Movement (Box 10)
    - The Hindemith Madrigale: An Analysis, 2 copies (Box 10)
    - An Historical Survey of the Development of the Pre-Bach Cantata with Emphasis on Franz Tunder and Dietrich Buxtehude (Box 10)
    - An Historical Survey of the Development of the Pre-Bach Cantata with Emphasis on Franz Tunder and Dietrich Buxtehude [2nd copy] (Box 11)
    - Music in Western Civilization Part III: c. 1800-1900+, 2 copies (Box 11)
    - Proposal for Registration of a Program in Music Education (Box 11)
    - Where it's Always Warm (Box 11)
  - By others
    - Report of the Long Range Planning Task Force Mission and Curriculum for the Board of Trustees [of Hobart and William Smith Colleges] (Box 11)
    - Typed pieces by Diane Stevenson (Box 11)